Apartment 248, 2 Munday Street, Manchester M4 7BG madhinhussain@gmail.com 07590 271997

Madhin Hussain

Experienced Assistant Merchandiser with a demonstrated history of working in the retail industry. Strong merchandising professional with a Master's degree in Applied Economics. Excellent team player with proven organisational, planning and communication skills, who thrives in challenging, fast paced environments.

EXPERIENCE

October 2020 - June 2021 (9 months)

ASSISTANT MERCHANDISER

Boohoo Group PLC

- Maximise profitability by ensuring best possible cost prices and BIM %.
- · Communicate regularly with suppliers to ensure deliveries are kept on time and resolve
- · issues when appropriate.
- Manage promotional activity by forecasting MD spend and building promotional models.
- Lead and manage the MAA's and assume responsibility for training and development.
- Trade the range Identify and utilise key trends to effectively trade department sales and
- · make decisions about future season strategy.
- O August 2019 October 2020 (1 year 3 months)

ASSISTANT MERCHANDISER

ASOS PLC

- Responsible for core flow product of 50+ options on Mens Knitwear & Socks taking monthly sales of £1m+.
- Manage stock intake by analysing stock and sales reports on weekly basis.
- Maximise profitability by ensuring stock is allocated to correct distribution hubs through analysis of stock and commitment mixes/
- Communicate regularly with suppliers to ensure deliveries are kept on time and resolve issues when appropriate.
- Manage promotional activity by forecasting MD spend and building promotional models.
- Lead and manage the MAA's and assume responsibility for training and development.
- Trade the range Identify and utilise key trends to effectively trade department sales and make decisions about future season strategy.
- O July 2017 August 2019 (2 years 2 months)

ASSISTANT MERCHANDISER

Next PLC

- Responsible for socks and hosiery departments, overseeing 240+ options with a seasonal budget of £10M+.
- Control and manage critical path with buying team in accordance with strategy.
- Formulate season strategy and present it to senior members of the team in Reviews.
- Communicate regularly with suppliers to ensure deliveries are kept on time and resolve issues when appropriate.
- Manage promotional activity by forecasting MD spend and building promotional models.
- Lead and manage the MAA's and assume responsibility for training and development.
- Trade the range Identify and utilise key trends to effectively trade department sales and make decisions about future season strategy.
- Manage and propose changes to the supplier base (current and new) to ensure effective management of the buying process.

O January 2016 - April 2017 (1 year 4 months)

ASSISTANT MERCHANDISER

Arcadia Group Ltd (Dorothy Perkins)

- Maintain department WSSI's and forecast sales and stocks by analysing weekly performance.
- Provide trading commentary for Monday meetings and make recommendations and take actions where appropriate.
- Work closely with buying and senior merchandising team to plan season and build option plan / line details.
- Actively manage intake against intake plan on WSSI, pushing and pulling intake forward when required and building relationships with suppliers.
- Manage promotional activity by forecasting MD spend and building promotional models.
- Lead and manage the MAA's and assume responsibility for training and development.
- O August 2014 December 2015 (1 year 5 months)

ASSISTANT MERCHANDISER ECOMMERCE

New Look Retailers Ltd

- Responsible for analysing and reporting on a specific set of categories online.
- Oversee 3 Ecommerce MAA's taking accountability of their roles and contribution to business and assume responsibility of training and development.
- Management and planning of stock intake for E-commerce based on WSSI.
- Prepare and lead trade updates to business on weekly basis.
- Optimising customer journey on site by analysing web metrics (clicks, visits, conversion, etc.)
- Responsible for Recommendations tool which provides alternatives and add on purchases to customers on site.
- Liaise regularly with core teams to plan key intake options and their presentation & navigation on site.
- O July 2012 August 2014 (2 years 2 months)

SENIOR MERCHANDISE ADMIN ASSISTANT

New Look Retailers Ltd

- Intake Management: Day to day management of intake and relationship with supplier to ensure goods are delivered on time.
- Reporting: Responsible for producing daily sales and feedback to team.
- Distribution: Managing future intake and setting targets for distribution according to WSSI.
- PO Maintenance: Responsible for making sure all PO attributes are up to date.
- · Assisting Manager in producing reports and meeting deadlines.

EDUCATION

October 2010 - September 2011

MSc APPLIED ECONOMICS

University of Westminster

O September 2006 – June 2010

BA HONS BUSINESS MANAGEMENT - MARKETING

University of Westminster

O September 2004 – July 2006

3 A LEVELS - HISTORY, ECONOMICS & GENERAL STUDIES

Sir George Monoux College